rishisoni6071@gmail.com

Indore (M.P.), India +91-9754370193

Professional Summary:

Started as an Intern in Web function, worked as Frontend Development Intern with Technocolabs, with Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd., and The Spark Foundation. Have the knowledge in various programming languages and regular coder on HackerRank and GeeksForGeeks. And Hands-on Experience on RPA as well.

Experience:

> Organization : Apisero Global Integration Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Profile : Software Engineer From - To : Aug 2021 – Current

> Organization : The Spark Foundation

Profile : Web Development & Designing Intern

From - To : Mar 2021 – Apr 2021

Organization : Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
Profile : Frontend Development Intern

From - To : Aug 2020 – Nov 2020

Organization : Technocolabs.tech

Profile : Web Development Intern

From - To : Jun 2020 – Aug 2020

Technical Skills:

Languages: Python 3, Core Java, SQL, JavaScript, C, HTML5, CSS3.

Software Tools: VS Code, Eclipse.

- > Other Tools: Git, Postman, Trello, Bitbucket, Slack, Jira, WordPress.
- Good Understanding in Data Structures Concepts.
- Good working experience with web services integration (REST API, JSON, Ajax).
- Experience in working with Libraries such as React, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize.
- Hands-on Experience on RPA's Automation Anywhere Tool to create Bots.

Education Qualification:

- Pursuing **Bachelor of Technology** from Shivajirao Kadam Institute of Technology & Management (Acropolis Technical Campus), Indore affiliated to Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya with specialization in **Computer Science** (2018-2022).
- ➤ Higher Secondary School Certificate (10+2) from MP State Board in 2018 with 82.80%.
- Secondary School Certificate (10th) from MP State Board in the year 2016 with 86.16%.

Internships & Projects Undertaken:

Organization : Technocolabs.techURL : Technocolabs Tech

➤ Application : Putatoe Web App

Role : Frontend Web DeveloperOrganization : Putatoe Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

➤ URL : <u>Putatoe - Web App</u>

➤ **Application** : Payment Gateway & Social Media Integration

➤ Role : Web Development & Designing Intern

Organization : The Spark Foundation

➤ URL : Payment-Gateway and Social-Media-Login

➤ Application : Nidhiswaram Fashion
 ➤ Role : Frontend UI Developer
 ➤ Organization : Freelance Project
 ➤ URL : Nidhiswaram Fashion

Personal Projects:

➤ Minor Project: Vocal for Local eCommerce Web Application.

➤ **ReactJS Projects**: News Website, Weather Forecast, Covid-19 Tracker, Currency-Converter, and To-Do List Apps.

- ➤ JavaScript Projects: Tic-Tac-Toe Game, Job-Portal, Hackathon Website, Portfolio Website, & SDKs Integration.
- ➤ **UI Development Projects**: Developed various Responsive Frontend Web Designs such as Bookstore, Business Portfolio, Coffee-Shop, etc.

Achievements:

- ➤ Regular Coder on GeeksForGeeks and solved approx. 150+ problems on Data Structures.
- > Five Star Rated in Python, SQL, and Java on HackerRank.
- Skills Certified in CSS, SQL, and Java on HackerRank.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth : 06/07/2001

Gender : Male **Nationality** : Indian

Languages known: Hindi, English

Mother Tongue : Hindi

Father's Name : Mr. Vinod Kumar Soni